Support Admin Watch on
kissasia.cam or kisskh.org
9 YEARS AGO
GYEONGWONJIN, HAMGYEONG PROVINCE
The barbarians!
THE NITANGGAE REBELLION
The Jurchens are invading.
Close the gate now! Deploy our forces!
Do not fear!
Stay strong! Guard your posts!
Siyul.
Mama. Mom.
You need to keep quiet.
Stay back! Stay back!
You damn wretches.
Filthy little worms!
Fuck!
No! Mom!
You maggots!
Mom?
Mom.
Chun! This child is still alive.
I can hear him breathing. He's breathing.
The Murky Stream
THREE. A STRONG NEW MAN
Find them!
Hey! Do you realize
who you just beat up back there?
Who?
He was the second son of Jo Daein,
the Uiju county magistrate.
Was that funny?
Does having such a title,
allow you to harass women
like he does?
Goodbye to the real world.
Now!
Easy there, huh.
Watch your back.
You're too slow.
- Watch your own back.
- Hey.
Let's go!
Let's go! Come on!
Get them!
Do you think they're already here?
Get behind if you're scared.
Now!
Let's see who cracks first.
You want a government job.
But you are always fighting like this.
You know how blunt Siyul can be.
I told you to help him steer clear
of trouble.
What if
the two of you end up getting arrested?
Forget passing the state exam, then.
Let alone the military exam!
Just how thoughtless can you be?
Siyul, you're next.
- What?
- Come here.
Ow!
Your chance.
I deeply regret
what I--
- Please!
- Quit your whining and stand right here.
Right now!
- Sorry! Sorry! Mother!
- Look at you! Be a man!
When are you gonna grow up?
- When are you gonna grow up?
- Is anyone at home?
What kind of trouble are you in now?
Huh?
Good evening. We are from Nokmyeongso.
What does that mean?
We evaluate
the applicants' qualifications.
Does a Jang Siyul reside here?
Are you Jang Siyul, then?
Yes.
Is your grandmother Oksan Hwang Clan,
name Jaun?
Is that correct?
Yes. That's correct.
What's wrong?
Is there a problem here?
She remarried, according to the records.
Due to that, you are not qualified
to take the exam.
Wait. What do you mean by that?
Choosing to remarry is considered
inappropriate behavior.
As a result, her descendants,
any children or grandchildren,
are barred from taking the state exam.
I'm surprised
your mother never explained this to you.
I lost her when I was a child.
I was too young.
Here. Take it.
JANG SIYUL
You're stopping him from taking the exam
just because his grandmother remarried?
It's unfortunate. We're only messengers.
DENIED QUALIFICATION
If you think the decision is unfair,
you can appeal the government
to reconsider.
Well, then.
Wait, sir! Sir!
You could get a recommendation
from the district magistrate.
Then, we will reconsider.
Magistrate! Magistrate sir!
Your subject is requesting
an audience, sir!
How can you just stay inside?
I just want a chance to take the exam.
Is that really so much to ask?
How many must we tell you, no?
You leave me no choice!
I'll see what the problem is.
How dare you!
Have you no manners?
Magistrate!
Are you listening in there, sir?
As a child, war came for us.
We faced an attack from the barbarians!
You officials were the first
to abandon their posts.
People kept screaming at them for help.
And one by one, they were cut down
with the sword.
That's what happened to my poor mother!
You officials, the barbarians,
how can you say one is any better
than the other?
- Come here.
- Magistrate!
It seems this savage...
doesn't know how to be grateful.
- Tear his tongue out.
- Punish this ingrate.
You would hit an unarmed man?
What kind of officials are you?
I wanted to be an official to...
protect the weak and--
I couldn't save my mother's life.
I wanted to be an official...
so I can protect my family!
If the country abandons the people,
then who are we supposed to believe in!
Everything's the same. Nothing changed.
Should I call him a tiger
caught in a trap,
or a dhole running wild?
It seems he caused quite the commotion.
He injured a number of soldiers.
- And then...
- What?
It happened.
- He got himself in real trouble.
- He killed someone, didn't he?
No! Too obvious. Use this.
- That boy...
- Yeah.
set fire to the official buildings there.
And every single one of them
set aflame instantly.
- Fire!
- If he's caught,
- he'll be decapitated anywhere.
- Fire!
While everyone was busy
putting the fire out,
someone dragged Jang Siyul out of there.
A masked man, or so they say.
And the man who took him...
His brother, though not his blood,
Jung Chun, they say,
at least according to the rumors,
you know?
It's upside down.
So this Jung Chun,
is it the same as that one?
Ah!
It's just a rumor.
There's no way to know for sure.
- Shit!
- Come here.
It's suspicious, though, isn't it?
Look here.
The name of the sender written here,
the newly appointed assistant officer.
And where is he from?
Hamgyeong.
You...
You need to turn around.
Siyul...
The state test will be soon, brother.
If you don't make it,
I can never face Mother again.
Go now.
You need to run far from here.
You need to survive, understand?
One day, the world will change.
Keep going.
Until that day.
Today is Mother's Jesa.
She was brave even when she was dragged
to the government office and tortured.
But then last winter,
she got sick and passed away.
And it was all my fault.
I shouldn't have gone as wild as I did.
Siyul,
we are not just friends.
We're brothers.
Don't forget to hold Mother's Jesa.
I plan on leaving for the border soon.
Why the border?
There is a war going on right now.
If I distinguish myself,
I heard my charges could get cleared.
You can't.
You could die in a battle.
You're an official.
And I'm a criminal.
Staying here
would expose you to more danger.
I had a wish...
to see you again before I died,
and here we are.
I got my wish.
Siyul.
Please...
be a good official.
Please.
Where are you off to?
Come work for me.
I'm Park Mudeok.
If you let me, I can change your life.
You should mind your own business.
You'd be wise to take my hand, eh?
Jang Siyul!
Jang Siyul, right?
You're Jang Siyul, aren't you?
They wouldn't let you take the state exam,
so you charged into the office,
and you burned it all down.
I don't know anyone around here
who would think to pull that shit.
That's great. Good job.
How did you know?
What's it matter how?
What matters is that the two of us
are together now.
What do you want from me, then?
The Mapo territory can be ours
with your brute strength
and your courage.
The way I look at it,
you were always meant to be a bandit.
I'm not interested in being a bandit.
Nor am I cut out for it.
I get to decide that.
Just report me to the officials, then.
What?
I only carried on because I didn't die.
I'm going now.
Go ahead.
Report me if that's what you want.
I don't care what you do.
Really?
All right, fine.
Wait. What about Jung Chun?
He helped you escape
when you set the government office
on fire.
On top of getting you out of there,
he now holds
an assistant officer position.
Now, what if I were to go
and report that to the officials, huh?
I don't know what you're talking about.
You don't know him, you say?
I saw something in your bundle.
Huh?
Was it a letter?
Is it still in there, you idiot?
If you don't give it back,
I really will kill you.
Go ahead.
Just do it.
Where would that letter end up if I die?
The police will wanna see it.
Huh?
Wow! Look at those damn eyes.
What did I tell ya?
You were always meant to be a bandit.
Huh?
You're wrong.
- That's not who I am.
- Hey.
If you listen to me,
you'll live.
And your friend will live, too.
What? You don't like it?
All right, then.
Never mind.
What do you want me to do for you?
You see,
I don't like to offer my hand
to someone who already turned me down.
Got it?
But for you? For you, I'll let it slide.
Grab it.
What are you waiting for?
Grab my foot.
Remember this, okay?
This right here.
This is where we stand.
You hear me?
My friend.
If anything happens to him,
I really will kill you.
Oh, shit.
You're scaring me, kid.
Hey.
I don't make it a habit of saying this
to other men.
You're mine from here on out.
Got it?
Captain Park?
- Captain Park?
- Yes?
The barn is short a few horses.
Horses?
I bring this issue up
because it says there are 20 in here.
In the barn, there were only three.
Well, I... I wasn't the one
who kept the ledger.
I wouldn't know about that.
Captain, you have to know
what the status of the horses are.
Officer Jung, I am highly disappointed.
There may be mistakes
due to heavy workloads.
I swear to the heavens,
I have no reason for remorse.
The armory looks empty as well.
Is this everything?
Why are you picking everything apart?
What's wrong?
You've not enjoyed your stay?
I'm not picking on anything.
It's just that it's a far cry
from the logbooks you've been submitting.
Why are all the swords and spears rusted
like this?
Rust can always be cleaned.
- I think you can lighten up a little.
- Can you bring the hwapo here?
It's been a while since we cleaned it.
I don't know if it'll fire at this point.
The armory is empty.
Neither the rations nor the horses
match the ledger.
At this point, if war breaks out,
we'll be absolutely helpless here.
Insolent!
That kind of arrogance
can get us in trouble here.
We are not the ones to take measures.
That authority is the General's,
far greater than where our powers lie.
Then I'll take it to the General
so I can seek real measures.
Sure, go right ahead.
He's not there, though.
Don't you remember?
We're throwing you a welcome party today.
Guests are coming from Hanseong City.
I already told you to be ready for it.
For goodness' sake!
How did you place first in the exam?
Consider me nothing more
than a mere woodpecker.
I just peck, your Grace, if you allow me.
I wish you nothing but the best, General.
I knew it.
You're the only one in our bureau
who works hard,
and the only reveler as well.
You sincerely honor me, General.
Now we have a newly appointed officer.
And as per tradition,
we shall drink from the bottle.
So let us celebrate.
All right.
Here!
To unending loyalty
and endless alcohol.
To us, the military!
Here, here, here,
here, here, here!
Now that this old man's danced his dance,
it's only right that the young man dances.
- Yeah! Yeah!
- Come on! Show us your moves!
Here.
Oh!
Would you look at that?
What a pretty official!
What exactly is the meaning of this?
You dare?
Our young official here
isn't excited enough!
He needs to dance!
Here we go!
Look at this.
What kind of military official
can't hold his liquor?
Goodness!
I worry about the future of this country.
We agree about that.
They say a fish rots from the head, but...
I struggle to find a spot in this city
that doesn't smell.
You can stop your lofty speech now.
Head on inside.
I experienced war as a young boy.
The soldiers were no different then.
Passing the time by drinking,
and they were always the first to run.
Who is it that protects the commoners
if the officials care only for pleasure?
What an arrogant assistant officer
we have here.
Looking after the people isn't what we do.
We're only here to protect His Majesty.
Protecting the citizenry?
That's the king's authority,
so that's his purview.
Are you the king now?
Do you want his position?
This kid.
You should watch your mouth, all right?
Getting outed as a traitor
doesn't take a lot.
Wow.
Eat up.
- Thank you so much
- Let me try that.
Yeah.
You look like you're a decent man.
Why are you with these good-for-nothings?
Your life must have been nice and cushy.
How else could you be so good with those?
I know.
You use chopsticks like a nobleman.
Very classy.
Ah! I need to learn how to do that.
Oh! Just...
By the way, we all know that there's
a pecking order in this class.
Am I not next after you?
Isn't it wrong that the new boy
gets to sit here?
It's wrong.
Well, then fight for it.
Huh? What?
I mean, if you win, you're the boss,
and if you lose you're the underling.
That's right.
He's about to get his teeth knocked out.
Let's see it.
Brother, you should fight him.
Uh, no, no, no.
All of you need to be quiet.
We can't fight. We're--
Look at him.
- He's a flincher.
- Look at this stuck-up jackass.
My name's Walwal, by the way.
I'm the youngest. Malbok.
Call me Jungbok.
I read the room and talk fast.
I'm Gaechun.
Open up. Ah!
Oh? Well...
How old are you? It's just...
Wait. What do you want to know that for?
Uh, I mean, I think you look older.
I wouldn't say I'm much older.
Besides,
seniority isn't set by age here.
It's set by the fist.
Still, that's a bit...
By the way, what's your name?
It's Siyul. Jang Siyul.
- Oh!
- Siyul.
Your name, even that's classy.
So classy.
- And he burned down a building.
- Huh?
Arson of a government office.
Really?
- Everything was burned to the ground.
- Wow.
I never would have expected that.
Now, that is a man.
I didn't realize
what a brave person you are.
I hope that you can forgive me, brother.
That is a man.
That's a real man!
Brother,
- I have to respect that.
- Me too.
See that, huh?
You are meant to be a bandit.
I'll be the forefinger again.
I'll lie on silk bedding
and piss in a golden chamber pot, huh?
- Gold chamber pot? Oh, yeah?
- Hey, hey.
When you're walking around town, huh,
you spot a tile-roof house,
claim that shit.
How about the one over there?
I know.
What about Gyeongbokgung Palace?
That'd be a nice place to buy.
If the King puts it on the market,
I'll snatch it.
Here. Eat a lot.
Keep your eyes fierce,
'cause tomorrow,
I'll be the forefinger again.
Don't we have wine? Go and get it.
Wait. What does that mean?
We're drinking tonight!
Five majigi of rice paddy,
and three majigi of farmland in Anseong.
This much will suffice as collateral.
We can lend up to 200 nyang.
You have until the second day
of next year.
We need to receive the full amount
plus additional interest.
Do you understand?
Yes, I understand.
I'll need your signature up front.
The money we lent.
How much was it all together?
Uh...
Sampo Market
and the Gyeonggang River combined
is around 270,000 nyang.
Don't forget
the promissory notes.
There are about 500,000 nyang.
Including guilds in other regions,
and if we factor in
all the small merchants,
the math is sound to me.
And then, we have to pay the government.
That's a little more than five hal.
If we could spend half of that,
we could build a few more bridges here.
Tomorrow is a busy day.
We're sending Seokchon their items.
We must load before the sunrise.
Do try to get some sleep, young lady.
Getting some fresh air?
How do you think Eun
is taking to the trade?
From what I can see,
I'd say your daughter was born for this.
Are you saying she is talented?
She inherited your blood
right down to her bones.
I see.
She and I were cut from the same cloth,
is that it?
I didn't mean to say that.
It's fine.
Who could know her any better than I?
I approve of her.
Make sure the dawn duty is on schedule.
I'll ensure it is done.
My lady!
My lady, you must come. There's a problem.
What happened?
Another guild paid the rush charge,
my lady.
So, the order was moved around.
We need those laborers.
It's their scheme.
This is how the bandits cheat us.
As of now, the bandits are blocking
our loading crew.
- I will speak to them, then.
- My lady, there would be no point.
- Surely they'll listen to reason.
- Bandits are not capable of diplomacy.
For the boat to leave on time,
we must load now.
If we don't move at once,
we will lose our items and our integrity.
I recommend paying the charge.
It will resolve all of this.
Do you know how many laborers we have?
Why do you ask?
We don't have time now.
We will load the boat with our laborers.
My lady, it would be unwise
to provoke the bandits.
This problem is bigger than money.
You must know that, too.
Summon all the laborers we can.
Prepare some torches as well.
I will try, my lady.
All right. Everyone, gather around.
Yes.
From here on, we will do this ourselves.
We will load the items directly.
Now, then.
What are they doing?
- Hey, Walwal.
- Huh?
Do we have money for the torch charge?
- They didn't.
- Oh!
So they think they can just pull one
over on us.
Here.
Hey! Put those torches down now!
What do you think you're doing?
Who the fuck thinks they can work my port
without paying the damn torch charge?
The torches we're using are ours,
and we brought our own oil.
So tell me,
why do I have to pay you for that?
What are you blabbering about,
little girl?
Maybe I'm getting old because
I don't understand a word you're saying.
Mudeok, we're in a rush.
Let it slide this once.
Chief Kang, you already know.
If you pay a lot,
that means you're very busy.
But if you don't,
you're only a little busy.
You've been around here long enough.
What's gotten into you?
Oh.
Don't tell me it's because
your new leader is this young lady.
So you wanna learn to trade?
I suggest you start by learning the rules
if you want to last around here.
Don't you agree?
She's scary? Look at that glare.
I am not interested
in playing along with bandits.
Oh, my.
All of you, grab your cargo and follow me.
- Right now!
- Don't move a muscle.
Do you want to get your legs broken?
If I see you move an inch, hmm,
I'll break your legs
right there on the spot.
- Okay?
- I welcome you to try.
But you'll face the consequences.
Don't stand there.
Go move the cargo.
Hurry. Do as Lady Eun says.
This might just be treasonous, bitch.
Hey, what should we do, brother?
Hey, come here.
Get over here.
Hmm.
I have a job for you.
You go and take the bitch's torch away.
Must we?
I thought I taught you to shut up
and do whatever I say.
Yet with each passing day,
you're just getting more arrogant.
Hey, did you forget I own you now?
I can make it so both you and your friend
lose your heads, yeah?
If you don't want that,
bring me that torch right away.
Just hold it.
Yeah. That's it.
How dare you! Halt!
Hey, you! Get back, will you?
Stay out of the way!
- Relax! Take it easy.
- Stop! Listen!
I'm here... to take your torch.
If the guild keeps pressing ahead,
then the laborers here
cannot make a living.
They'll still make a living.
It's just that you won't be able
to rip anyone off.
It's no use complaining to me, my lady.
The torch.
What the hell is this shit?
Hey! Are you trying to court her?
Why aren't you restoring order?
Wow!
He's a bandit now, through and through.
Listen up!
Our country's peace depends
on the bandit standing tall.
Put out that fire.
That's right.
Grab them all.
Put down the torches!
Put out the fire, all of you.
Is this the justice you wanted?
I thought you were a hard worker.
But it turns out you're nothing
but a bloodsucking leech.
Fine then.
Enjoy this life.